and they taught me humor. My personality switched from being shy and awkward to being defiant and cursing out a storm. Needless to say, I did not have many friends. I was also hypersensitive to texture. The feel of water on my skin was like pins and needles, and so for years, I refused to shower. I can assure you that my hygiene routine is up to standards now, though. (Laughter) I had to do a lot to get here, and my parents -- things kind of got out of control when I was sexually assaulted by a peer, and on top of everything, it made a difficult situation worse. And I had to travel 2,000 miles across the country to get treatment, but within days of them prescribing a new medication, my life turned into an episode of the Walking Dead. I became paranoid, and began to hallucinate that rotting corpses were coming towards me. My family finally rescued me, but by that time, I had lost 19 pounds in those three weeks, as well as developing severe anemia, and was on the verge of suicide. I transferred to a new treatment center that understood my aversions, my trauma, and my social anxiety, and they knew how to treat it, and I got the help I finally needed. And after 18 months of hard work, I went on to do incredible things. One of the things with Asperger's is that oftentimes, these people have a very complex inner life, and I know for myself, I have a very colorful personality, rich ideas, and just a lot going on in my mind. But there's a gap between where that stands, and how I communicate it with the rest of the world. And this can make basic communication a challenge. Not many places would hire me, due to my lack of social skills, which is why I applied to Waffle House. (Laughter) Waffle House is an exceptional 24-hour diner -- (Applause) thank you -- where you can order your hash browns the many ways that someone would dispose of a human corpse ... (Laughter) Sliced, diced, peppered, chunked, topped, capped, and covered. As social norms would have it, you should only go to Waffle House at an ungodly hour in the night. (Laughter) So one time, at 2 am, I was chatting with a waitress, and I asked her, "What's the most ridiculous thing that's happened to you on the job?" And she told me that one time, a man walked in completely naked. (Laughter) I said, "Great! Sign me up for the graveyard shift!" Needless to say, Waffle House did not hire me. So in terms of having Asperger's, it can be viewed as a disadvantage, and sometimes it is a real pain in the butt, but it's also the opposite. It's a gift, and it allows me to think innovatively. At 19, I won a research competition for my research on coral reefs, and I ended up speaking at the UN Convention of Biological Diversity, presenting this research. (Applause) Thank you. And at 22, I'm getting ready to graduate college, and I am a co-founder of a biotech company called AutismSees. (Applause) Thank you. But consider what I had to do to get here: 25 therapists, 11 misdiagnoses, and years of pain and trauma. I spent a lot of time thinking if there's a better way, and I think there is: autism-assistive technology. This technology could play an integral role in helping people with autistic spectrum disorder, or ASD. The app Podium, released by my company, AutismSees, has the ability to independently assess and help develop communication skills. In addition to this, it tracks eye contact through camera and simulates a public-speaking and job-interview experience. And so maybe one day, Waffle House will hire me, after practicing on it some more. (Laughter) And one of the great things is that I've used Podium to help me prepare for today, and it's been a great help. But it's more than that. There's more that can be done. For people with ASD -- it has been speculated that many innovative scientists, researchers, artists, and engineers have it; like, for example, Emily Dickinson, Jane Austen, Isaac Newton, and Bill Gates are some examples. But the problem that's encountered is that these brilliant ideas often can't be shared if there are communication roadblocks. And so, many people with autism are being overlooked every day, and they're being taken advantage of. So my dream for people with autism is to change that, to remove the roadblocks that prevent them from succeeding. One of the reasons I love lucid dreaming is because it allows me to be free, without judgment of social and physical consequences. When I'm flying over scenes that I create in my mind, I am at peace. I am free from judgment, and so I can do whatever I want, you know? I'm making out with Brad Pitt, and Angelina is totally cool with it. (Laughter) But the goal of autism-assistive technology is bigger than that, and more important. My goal is to shift people's perspective of autism and people with higher-functioning Asperger's because there is a lot they can do. I mean, look at Temple Grandin, for example. And by doing so, we allow people to share their talents with this world and move this world forward. In addition, we give them the courage to pursue their dreams in the real world, in real time. Thank you. (Applause)
y ellos me enseñaron el sentido del humor. Mi personalidad cambió y pasé de ser tímida y torpe a ser desafiante y maldecir como un marinero. No hace falta decir que no tenía muchos amigos. Era hipersensible a las texturas. El agua sobre mi piel me daba una sensación de hormigueo y por eso, durante años, me negué a ducharme. Les aseguro que ahora mi higiene ha vuelto a los niveles normales. (Risas) Tuve que trabajar mucho para llegar hasta aquí y mis padres... las cosas se salieron de control cuando fui agredida sexualmente por un compañero, por lo cual, una situación ya difícil empeoró aún más. Viajé más de 3000 kilómetros y atravesar el país para recibir tratamiento y a pocos días después de que me recetaran un nuevo medicamento, mi vida se convirtió en un episodio del Walking Dead. Me volví paranoica y empecé a alucinar viendo cadáveres putrefactos que se me acercaban. Mi familia finalmente me rescató, pero para entonces, había perdido 9 kilos en esas tres semanas, además de haber desarrollado una anemia severa y estar al borde del suicidio. Me trasladaron a un nuevo centro de salud donde entendían mis aversiones, mi trauma y mi ansiedad social, y sabían cómo tratarlos, y recibí por fin la ayuda que necesitaba. Y después de 18 meses de duro trabajo, pasé a hacer cosas increíbles. Una de las cosas que pasan cuando uno tiene Asperger es, que muchas veces, estas personas tienen una vida interior muy compleja, y lo sé de primera mano: tengo una personalidad muy exuberante estoy llena de ideas y tengo un montón de cosas en la cabeza. Pero hay una brecha entre donde ocurre todo esto y cómo lo comunico al resto del mundo. Y esto puede hacer de una comunicación básica un desafío. Pocas empresas estaban dispuestas a contratarme, debido a mi falta de habilidades sociales, razón por la cual presenté mi solicitud en Waffle House. (Risas) Waffle House es un restaurante excepcional abierto las 24 horas (Aplausos) --gracias-- donde puedes pedir tus patatas fritas de las mismas numerosas maneras en las que también te puedes deshacer de un cadáver humano... (Risas) en rodajas, a dados, sazonadas, en trozos, recubiertas, rebozadas, o ahogadas. De acuerdo a las normas sociales solo hay que ir a Waffle House a horas intempestivas de la noche. (Risas) Así que una vez, a las 2 de la mañana, estaba charlando con una camarera y le pregunto: "¿Qué es lo más ridículo que te ha pasado en el trabajo?" Y me dijo que una vez entró un hombre completamente desnudo. (Risas) Le dije: "¡Fantástico, me apunto para el turno de la noche!" No hace falta mencionar que Waffle House no me contrató. Padecer de Asperger puede ser visto como una desventaja, y a veces es un asunto realmente desagradable pero también puede ser una ventaja. Es un regalo, y me permite pensar de manera creativa. A los 19 años, gané un concurso de investigación con mi trabajo sobre los arrecifes de coral, y llegué hasta la Convención sobre la Diversidad Biológica de la ONU para presentar esta investigación. (Aplausos) Gracias. Y a los 22, estoy a punto de terminar la universidad, también soy cofundadora de una empresa de biotecnología llamada AutismSees. (Aplausos) Gracias. Pero veamos lo que tuve que hacer para llegar hasta aquí: 25 terapeutas, 11 diagnósticos erróneos, y años de dolor y trauma. Pasé mucho tiempo pensando si hay una forma mejor, y creo que es la tecnología de apoyo para el autismo. Esta tecnología podría desempeñar un papel fundamental para ayudar a las personas con trastornos del espectro autista, o TEA. La aplicación Podio, lanzada por mi compañía AutismSees, tiene la capacidad de hacer evaluaciones independientes y ayudar a desarrollar habilidades de comunicación. Además de esto, hace un seguimiento del contacto visual a través de una cámara y simular un discurso o una entrevista de trabajo. Así que tal vez un día, Waffle House me contratará después de practicar más con esta aplicación. (Risas) Y una de las cosas geniales es que he usado Podium para preparar la charla de hoy, y eso me ha ayudado mucho. Pero es más que esto. Se puede hacer mucho más. Para las personas con TEA... se ha especulado que muchos científicos innovadores, investigadores, artistas, e ingenieros lo padecen, como, por ejemplo, Emily Dickinson, Jane Austen, Isaac Newton y Bill Gates son algunos ejemplos. Pero se enfrentan al problema de que a menudo no pueden compartir estas ideas brillantes si la comunicación es un obstáculo. Por eso, muchas personas con autismo están siendo infravaloradas cada día y su potencial no se está aprovechado. Así que mi sueño para las personas con autismo es cambiar eso, eliminar los obstáculos que les impiden tener éxito. Una de las razones por las que me encanta soñar con los ojos abiertos es porque me permite ser libre, sin ser juzgada o sufrir consecuencias sociales o físicas. Cuando estoy volando en el entorno que puedo crear en mi mente, encuentro la paz. Nadie me juzga, así que puedo hacer lo que quiero, ¿saben? Salgo con Brad Pitt, y a Angelina no le molesta. (Risas) Pero el objetivo de crear tecnología de apoyo para el autismo es más grande que eso y más importante. Mi objetivo es cambiar la opinión de la gente sobre el autismo y de los que sufren de formas avanzadas de Asperger porque es mucho con lo que pueden contribuir. Quiero decir, veamos a Temple Grandin, por ejemplo. De esta manera, la gente puede compartir sus talentos con este mundo y ayudar al mundo a mejorar. Además, les alentamos a que persigan sus sueños en el mundo real, en tiempo real. Gracias. (Aplausos)